If you're a Type B, you need to take care.
If you leave it alone, it can become a serious,
life-threatening, situation.
Turn it off!
But worry not, for we'll reveal the solution to your problems!
This show is disgusting!
It's really nothing to be scared of...
How about a bath?
Am I gonna die too?
What?
What're you talking about? You're only six years old!
Sorry!
Bunny Drop
I dunno about tomorrow.
It's different than a sacrifice. Something's off.
I don't think it's like some penalty game.
So, why? I don't get it at all.
I'm a little bit unsatisfied, but your presence
right now is more than just important.
There's no such thing in this world
as something never-ending.
Crying isn't painful, it's love's sweet drops, sweet drops!
I want to keep dreaming forever, ya know?
I want to be more kind, ya know?
As long as I'm with you, I'm happy.
Girls sure are strong, ya know?
But sometimes we're weak, ya know?
Our wish is to be happy, happy, happy!
And those days will be happy, too!
Just wanna make you happy!
See you later!
If I don't decide on a kindergarten soon, I'll be screwed!
I've heard of talented people in huge companies
with day-care centers at the workplace...
Like hell, that'd be a company around here!
Kawachi!
Hey!
Kawachi, did you get a girlfriend?
What?!
You're going home early all the time these days...
Well, it's not that.
You always used to take the last train, right?
Last year, sales went through the roof because of you,
but if you stopped working as hard...
Look, I didn't make so many sales because of enthusiasm or tenacity.
I was just lucky.
After all, my name's Daikichi...
Kawachi!
Wait!
I'll take that.
Thanks!
You're going to the 4th floor, right?
Yep. Doing well, as always?
Not this year.
In fact, this guy was just pressuring me to do better.
Look, it's making me go bald.
It's tough after raising the bar so high, huh?
Hey Gotou, do you really have a child?
It's because I'm short, isn't it?
No, it's just that you're so thin, I can't picture you pregnant...
Yeah, me neither.
He's already two.
Thanks. Just put 'em down here.
I'll go with you.
Oh, I can manage.
All right...
See you!
She's as powerful as ever, y'know?
If only Gotou had stayed in sales...
She's worked here for years longer than I have,
but after getting pregnant, she requested a demotion
just so she could go home at the same time every day.
Everyone in the company was talking about her...
How long are you going to take care of her?!
We didn't really decide on that...
Rin, huh?
She's been wetting the bed lately.
I can tell that it really embarrasses her.
Maybe it's an emotional thing.
You'd be surprised at how much kids sweat,
though they don't do it as much in the fall or winter.
They pee more then.
I was always told...
"Pee before going to bed".
Her mother must've had her reasons.
I'd ask her if I could...
Mothers are important, aren't they?
If you're any kind of man, you'd never say die!
Hang in there!
What'd you do today?
I read picture books... and had a staring contest...
Was it fun?
What's that for?
Rin, I'm gonna make dinner now.
The moon's deflated, huh?
Hello?
Well, how's it going?
I'm fine, thanks...
I'm not asking about you.
Oh, right. She's fine.
Wait a second, I thought you didn't want to be involved.
You're the one that's taking care of her,
so I can't help but be involved.
I'm gonna try to find a clue about Rin's mother this weekend,
so I'll be out of your hair.
I see... Then give me a call when you reach the station.
Make sure you dress that girl warmly.
Yeah... I'll invite Haruko, too.
It seems she's friendly with her girl.
We passed another car!
Looks like you're having a good time...
Yeah!
We're here.
Welcome.
Rin, thanks for coming!
Hey!
I'm sorry, I don't have anything a kid would enjoy.
She likes old people stuff anyway. Right?
Are you done already?
Yeah.
Don't come crying to me if you're hungry later.
I'm stuffed...
I'm sorry I couldn't finish it.
I'm home!
Sorry I'm late!
That was awful!
What was with that annoying family?!
Brother!
You seriously took custody of her?!
Yeah...
And now for the weather.
It's sunny and warm all over the country today.
Temperatures in all regions are about
2 degrees higher than the average for this time of year,
making it pleasant weather everywhere.
I'm gonna head to the bathroom.
Now, let's look at the forecast for tomorrow.
I need to use the toilet!
I can't go with you sitting there!
Is she always like that?
No...
She's a lot more talkative at home.
She even had fun on the train, acting like she was going on a trip.
Now that we're here,
all we have to greet us are the uptight people who were at the funeral.
What're you trying to say?!
Moron. If the adults are in a bad mood, kids will think they did something wrong.
You're right...
It may have been that way for you kids, too.
See?! Insensitive as you are, you were the same way!
And Rin's smarter than you ever were!
Shut up, old man!
Rin, you like cat's cradle, don't you?
Come on, at least answer.
Yeah...
I'll give this one to you.
It's pretty...
Watch Auntie do it first, okay?
"Auntie"? You mean "Grandma", don't you?
You're not old enough to be my grandma!
Oh my! What a good girl!
It's because her standard for being old is crazy-high!
Watch me do it, all right?
Huh? Did I do it wrong?
What's this?
This? A 4-step ladder.
How nice!
A 2-step ladder.
An airplane.
A slide.
A diamond!
That's amazing.
It's easy with this kind of yarn.
Did you make this?
That's right. I knitted it from some thin wool.
Doing that makes it the perfect weight.
Much better than just making loops with woolen yarn.
I know! Since she's good with her hands, I bet she can do beanbags, too!
You hook it around your little finger like this...
L-Like this?
Yeah, that's it!
One, two, buckle my shoe. Three, four, knock at the door...
What is this?! What the heck is going on here?!
"What is this"? Isn't this what you wanted?!
Yes?
Who is it?
It might be Haruko.
Rin!
These are so pretty! What are they?
They're beanbags.
Thanks for coming.
You do it like this?
Like this?
No problem.
Like this. And you sing a song as you do it.
I'm really impressed that you can juggle working and raising a child.
It's hard!
My husband won't help at all.
Auntie taught me how to do it.
Who's Auntie?
Are you going to Grandpa's house from now?
Daikichi's mom.
That's not Auntie, that's Grandma!
Yeah... I thought I might find a clue about Rin's mother.
Isn't this a pretty string?
That makes sense...
It's really easy to use.
After all, I think having a mother is important.
Maybe I can do it well, too...
Go like this, then this...
Huh?
Strange...
Grandpa, you could've at least written a will.
Weren't you worried about Rin at all?!
A modem?
I'm back.
W-What's with that hair?!
She made it like Reina's!
Those aren't your clothes either...
They're Kazumi's!
Hah? Kazumi?
Mom, she can't wear old, out-of-style clothes like that!
But she looks so nice in them!
I guess...
They do look fine on her.
This brings back memories.
So, how was Grandpa's house?
These were from when you were 4, Kazumi.
I didn't find a single clue.
I see...
Either way, we probably shouldn't bug Rin about these things.
You're doing your best.
I don't think we ever told you this...
After you were born, Mom went back to work.
She wasn't a housewife the entire time?
When she was pregnant with Kazumi,
she wore herself too thin and had to be hospitalized.
Upon returning to work,
Mom found that they didn't want her anymore.
It made her so unhappy.
And Kazumi was so tiny when she was born...
Mom often took off work and came home early for you kids.
And what about Kazumi?
She gave Kazumi all of her attention,
so she became the arrogant and bossy woman you see now!
How are you on time? Do you want Dad to drop you off?
Nah, that's all right. We'll still make it in time if we walk.
Can we come back again?
She wants to know if she can come back again.
Auntie will be here waiting for you, so come back anytime.
Bye.
W-What are you talking about?!
What's wrong with wanting a grandchild?!
I'd take care of the baby...
I can't work and raise a child at the same time!
That's too much for just one woman!
Besides, I still wanna wear a swimsuit and go out drinking...
Hey, Rin, did Grandpa have a computer?
Do you even know what a computer is?
Yeah.
Did Grandpa use it?
The maid used it.
He had a maid?
Her name was Masako.
Maternal Health Record Masako Yoshii
W-What was she like?
I don't remember so much...
I don't like Masako...
She hated me and she was always angry.
I was scared of her...
That's why I don't think about her.
I see.
It's a little late to be saying this,
but it's tough to work full-time and raise a kid, isn't it?
You've got that right.
There's never a dull moment, that's for sure.
Did you ever feel like you were sacrificing yourself for your child?
Do you mean my demotion?
Sorry. I know I'm overstepping my bounds but...
I thought it was the best choice at the time,
and it turned out all right, so I have no problem with it.
If I ever did feel that though,
I wouldn't want to talk about it.
You know how powerful words can be, right?
What was it... "Saying it makes it true"?
Does that make sense?
No...
I understand exactly what you mean!
I hope you'll give me more advice in the future.
Kawachi, your child is older than mine, isn't she?
You should be giving me advice!
Rin...
You can wake me up.
But it's sweat!
It doesn't matter what it is.
Did you have a bad dream?
What's it like to die?
Daikichi, are you gonna die before me?
Sadness about Grandpa's death...
Anxiety over what would happen if I died...
Fear of her own death...
She isn't able to sort these things out, so she's a mess inside.
Rin, everything will be fine 'til you're a young woman.
When will I start to be a young woman?
I mean everything will be fine 'til you're a middle-aged lady.
Until then, I am not gonna die!
Count on it!
Okay.
And don't worry about wetting the bed either.
You'll be fine as long as you go to the toilet before bedtime.
The toilet is scary!
I'll go with you at night.
If you still have an accident after that,
all we have to do is change your pajamas.
Will you be mad?
It's nothing to be mad about, and it's nothing to be laughed at for, either.
Okay.
What did you want to talk to me about?
I'm sorry this is so sudden, Hidaka...
Well... this is out of the blue,
but I need you to transfer me to a department without overtime work!
What? Kawachi... Are you serious about this?
Completely serious!
I see. So that's what's been happening with you...
Personally, I think it's a real shame...
but I've got a kid, too.
I'll try my best to convince the section chief.
I'm sorry. I really appreciate your help.
You do know your men will make a fuss, right?
I don't get this!
Why'd it have to be you, Kawachi?!
Can't another relative take her?!
I can't tell him that I insisted on taking her in myself.
And aren't there nursery schools that'll keep the kids 'til late at night?!
I don't wanna work for anyone but you, Kawachi!
I know this is sudden...
but higher-ups often make sudden transfers.
Don't make a big deal out of this!
However... I really am sorry.
You'll all manage without me though.
They should be able to shuffle people around.
If not, then there's something seriously wrong with this place.
I can't let Rin go on like this!
I don't think...
I'm not making a bad decision...
Right?
Maybe...
Did you finish?
Is this enough rice?
Yeah, that's perfect!
Towel, lunch box, slippers, toothbrush, cup...
and your name on everything!
A futon?!
Oh, that's just for babies...
All right!
Daikichi, hurry up!
If you were to ask me right now, I'd be lying if I said this didn't feel like a sacrifice.
It'd be nice though, if I can look back on all this one day and say that she was worth every second.
A sunny early Sunday afternoon
Let's go somewhere today
It's the same road I'm used to traveling
But I can see it sparkling so bright
With the sun shining down its warmth
And you here by my side...
I'm already high, high, high
I feel like dashing out
Sing, la, la, la
My voice out to forever
I'm already high, high, high
Ride the dancing wind
Sing, la, la, la
My voice springs up
Rin, the thing on your towel and your lunch box...
What is it?
It looks like a dog with huge ears...
It's not a dog!
It's Lop Ear!
Lop...? It's a what?
A rabbit!
This isn't a little dog?
It's a rabbit!
Jeez!
Rin, let's go pee.
I already went!
Is that right?